Guide to the Rukhl Fishman Papers, 1940-1990
Department of Special Collections
Rukhl Fishman Papers,
1940-1990
M0778
Fishman, Rukhl, 1935-1984.
5.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection includes the papers of an American-born Yiddish poet living in Israel until her death in 1984. Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, poetry manuscripts, newsclippings, subject files, personal documents, and school/youth activities.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Partially restricted. For more information, contact the Manuscripts Librarian.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by Dr. and Mrs. Joshua A. Fishman, 1993.
Biography
Rukhl Fishman (RF), the younger sister of Joshua A. Fishman (JAF), was born June 10, 1935 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She was raised in a secular Yiddish-speaking home and her parents, Aaron and Sonia Fishman (AF and SF), were dedicated activists in local Yiddishist circles. RF attended Workmen's Circle elementary and high school from 1941-1949 and was a camper at Camp Boiberik, where her friends included Bina Silverman (later Weinreich) and Gella Schweid (later Fishman) (GSF). RF's early literary efforts were encouraged by the poet Malke Heifetz-Tusman in Los Angeles, California, where the family moved in 1949. While in Los Angeles RF became active in the Zionist youth movement Hashomer Hatsair and attended hakhsharot (agricultural training colonies) in New York and New Jersey after the family's return to the East Coast in 1953. In 1953 she met Theodor Holdheim, a mathematician and musician who had come to the U.S. as a shaliakh (emissary) from Hashomer Hatsair. They were married in 1954 and moved to Holdheim's kibbutz in Israel, Kibbutz Bet-Alpha. RF particularly loved the outdoor agricultural work on the kibbutz, which was to influence much of her poetry. RF continued her Yiddish literary activities in Israel. She was the youngest member of the group Yung yisroel (Young Israel) and often published in their journal of the same name. Avrom Sutzkever, one of the most distinguished modern Yiddish poets, encouraged her writing. Starting in 1956 he published her work in the leading Yiddish literary journal Di goldene keyt (The Golden Chain), of which he is the editor. RF spent the year 1972 in Jerusalem taking private lessons with the scholar Yudl Mark and courses in Yiddish and Hebrew Literature at the Hebrew University. In 1978 she won the Itsik Manger Prize for Yiddish Literature. From about 1957, RF showed signs of illness which was eventually diagnosed as Lupus. Her husband was also frequently ill during these years. RF had 9 miscarraiges, after which the couple adopted two sons, in 1964 and 1967. RF died on August 26, 1984. Theodor Holdheim died six months later. Four volumes of RF's poetry were published during her lifetime: Zun iber alts (Sun Over Everything) (1962), Derner nokhn regn (Thorns After the Rain) (1966), Himl tsvishn grozn/Shamayim be-eysev (Heaven Among the Grass) (1968), and Vilde tsig/Iza pziza (Wild Goat) (1976). The last two were published in bilingual editions with Hebrew translations by Arye Aharoni. A selection of her work in Yiddish and English translation, Azoy vil ikh faln/I Want To Fall Like This, was published in 1994 by Wayne State University Press (Detroit, Michigan).
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Incoming and outgoing correspondence, poetry manuscripts, newsclippings, subject files, personal documents, and school/youth activities.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Aharoni, Arye.; Ash, Khayele.; Basman Ben-Haim, Rivka.; Birstein, Yossel.; Eisenman, Tsvi.; Glanz-Leyeles, Aron.; Glatstein, Yankev.; Grade, Chaim.; Grosbard, Herts.; Grosman, Moyshe.; Heller, Binim.; Heifetz-Tusman, Malke.; Kazdan, Ch. Sh.; Korn, Rokhl.; Lehrer, Leybush.; Litvin, Mordkhe.; Mark, Yudl.; Meed, Vladke.; Miron, Dan.; Mlotek, Yosl.; Molodowsky, Kadia.; Noy, Dov.; Sadan, Dov.; Schaechter, Mordhke.; Shmeruk, Khone.; Singer, Isaac Bashevis.; Sutzkever, Avrom.; Turkow, Zigmunt.; Weinreich, Bina Silverman.; Weinreich, Max.; Weinreich, Uriel.; Yungman, Moyshe.; Yunin, Volf.; Zelitch, Yehude.; Yung yisroel.; Yiddish literature--Israel.; Yiddish poetry.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Correspondence, 1940-1984
  Subseries 1. Outgoing correspondence; Subseries 2. Incoming correspondence; Subseries 3. Other family members; Subseries 4. Miscellaneous
  - Subseries 1. Outgoing correspondence
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, 1940 Aug. 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron and Sonia Fishman, 1943 July (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, 1944 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, and Joshua A. Fishman, 1945 June - Aug. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1946 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1947 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Vladke Mead, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Tsui Eisenman,1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Also includes English letter from Theodor
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Esther Codor, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Also includes English from Theodor
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Avrom Sutzkever, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to HaKhevra HaYisraelit L'folklor v'Antroplogie (Hebrew), Moyshe Grossman, A. Verber, Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Moyshe Grossman, Avrom Sutzkever, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman (in English, from Theodor), A. Verber, Yehude Zelitch, Binim Heller, Monele Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman (in English, from Theodor), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Yehude Zelitch, Avrom Sutzkever, Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Leova and Dora Levin (telegram, in English), Mordkhe Schaechter, Tsvi Eisenberg, Rivke Basman, Mr. Rosenberg, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Khayim Barkan, Dr. & Mrs. Dzuba (in English), Aaron Fishman, and Sonia Fishman, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Aaron Fishman, and Sonia Fishman, Mordkhe Schaechter, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Also includes New Year calendars sent as gifts to Aaron Fishman & Sonia Fishman as well as to Joshua A. Fishman and Gella S. Fishman.
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Avrom Sutzkever, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Mr. Sharon, Mattis Olitski, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Sonia Fishman (in English, from Theodor), Yaakov Beker, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Secretary of the Association of Writers of [?] (in Hebrew), Mordkhe Khalomish (in Hebrew), Don Miron (in Hebrew), Asriel Alkhamni (in Hebrew), Committee - Beit Alpha (in Hebrew), Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Sonia Fishman, Monele Fishman, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman (includes English letter from Theodore), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Yitskhok Yonasovitsh, Eli Netser (in Hebrew), Kibbutz Beit Alpha (in Hebrew), Herts Grosbard, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Arye Shomri, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman, Yehude Zelitch, Eli [?] (in Hebrew), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Arye Shomri, Yudl Mark, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, and sons, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Also includes correspondence in Hebrew from Uri & Arik Hldheim, with drawings, and letter in English from Theodor.
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Dovid Shtokfish, Sonia Fishman, Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Also includes note with list of books
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Also includes letter in English from Theodor and letter from Uri Holdheim
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman, the President of Israel (in Hebrew), Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman (also includes letters from Uri & Arik, in Hebrew, and from Theodor, in English), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Also includes drafts of telegrams from Joshua A. Fishman, maps drawn by Theodor.
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Cindy Ragland (International Portland Review) (in English), A.E.R. Cohen (in Hebrew), Mordkhe Litvin, Eliyahu Tucker, Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman, Sonia Fishman, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Also includes letter in English toTheodor and to Uri & Arik in Hebrew.
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Yosl Birshteyn, Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman, Mrs. Hofsteyn, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman (& Theodor, in English), Avrom Sutzkever, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman (& Theodor, in English), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman (& Theodor, in English), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman (& Theodor, in English), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Also includes: copies of letters from Rukhl Fishman to Tamar & Bini Blumental (in Hebrew); report written by Rukhl Fishman on her medical condition (in Hebrew); copies of letters to Rukhl Fishman from Khave Ratson, Asher Rotem, and Bunim Shamir (in Hebrew); and copies of announcements and articles about Rukhl Fishman and Rukhl Fishman's death from Iraeli Yiddish press.
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman from Theodor (in English), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Sonia Fishman and Aaron Fishman, Theodor (in English), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Joshua A. Fishman & Gella S. Fishman, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Also includes letters from Uri & Ari (in Hebrew)
    - Fishman, Rukhl. Correspondence to Avrom Sutzkever; Esther Codor; Tsvi Luria; Hillel Khomski; Mical Janal (in English); Benyamin Halevi (in Hebrew); Yosl Birshteyn; Dr. Mordkhe Schaechter, editor of "Hasavua" (in Hebrew), [?] Blushteyn; [?] Revzin; Eliyahu Toker; [?] Shteynberg; Hadasah Rubin; Binim Heller; Arlene Seltzer (in English); Loitah [?]; Kalif [?] (in Hebrew).n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 2. Incoming correspondence
    - Correspondence in, 1944 Mar. 12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Silverman, Bine
    - Correspondence in, 1945 Mar. 24 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Cohen, Ira
    - Correspondence in, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Silverman, Bine; Fishman, Gella Schweid
    - Correspondence in, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Silverman, Bine; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Joshua A.; Meed, Vladka
    - Correspondence in, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Also includes envelope addressed to Rukhl Fishman containing advertisement.
      Weinreich, Bine; Weinreich, Uriel
    - Correspondence in, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Also contains sheet music from Khayem Barkan, Rukhl's teacher.
      Fishman, Joshua A.; Unger, Menashe; Weinreich, Bine; Barkan, Khayem
    - Correspondence in, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Fishman, Joshua A.; Bluestein, William
    - Correspondence in, 1952 Sept. 18 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Shamir, Bunim; Hashomer Hatzair
    - Correspondence in, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Gella Schweid; [?], Ruth; Cohen, Khanan; Yonai, Arien; Yonai, Gila; Miller, Sarah; Sofri, Beni; Winter, Ch.
    - Correspondence in, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Codor, Ester; Mikhal; Shore, Alex; Rossman, Ben; Rossman, Lillian; Levin, Unle Leva; Shapiro, Pepi; Shapiro, Martin; Shapiro, Stevie; Yonia, Ariyeh; Yonai, Gila; Yonai, Aliza; Waknin, Shoshana
    - Correspondence in, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Aaron; Eisenman, Tsvi; Kahn, Leybl; Kahn, Avrom; Bluestein, William; Silberman, Aaron; Silberman, Bella; Yiddish Dictionary Committee
    - Correspondence in, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Sonia; Bassman, Rivke; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Yisroel, Yung; Heifetz-Tussman, Malke; Eisenman, Tsvi; Yagur, Meshek; F., Khayem; Khane
    - Correspondence in, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Levin, Esther; Levin, Ali; Eisenman, Tsvi; Mark, Yudl; Karpinovitsh, Avrom
    - Correspondence in, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Rintsler, Avrom; F., Khayem; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Levin, Lyova; Grossman, Moyshe; Lehrer, Lipe; Silber, Clara; Hillely, P.
    - Correspondence in, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Weinreich, Bine; Weinreich, Uriel; Lehren, Leibush; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Sonia; Birshteyn, Yosl; Bialostotzky, B.J.; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Lehren, Leibush; Weissman, Gavriel; Grossman, Moyshe; Yosifin, Ts.; Helzner, Morry; Basman, Rivke; Weinreich, Regina; Rosenstein, Tevye; First World Congress for Jewish Folklore Research; Kibbutz HaMe'epil
    - Correspondence in, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Also includes copy of letter from Bine Weinreich to Joshua A. Fishman, Gella S. Fishman about Rukhl Fishman.
      Heifetz-Tussman, Malke; Weinreich, Bine; Tolpin, Marta; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Sonia; Birshteyn, Yosl; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.
    - Correspondence in, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Codor, Esther; Brandwin, Aliza; Sutzkever, Avrom; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Goldberg, Sonia; Heller, Binem; Khanl, Gila; Sturman, [?]; Verber, A.; Weil, Meyer; Weinreich, Bine; Weinreich, Uriel; I.L. Peretz Publishers
    - Correspondence in, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Letter from Zigmund Turkow includes photograph. Also includes 2 copies of a letter from Aaron Fishman and Sonia Fishman to Rukhl Fishman in English.
      Avani, L.; Basman, Rivke; Bez, Khayem; Bialostotzky, B.J.; Birshteyn, Yosl; Eisenman, Tsvi; Faner, Y.; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Gorin, Moyshe; Hashin, Dani; Hashin, Khave; Heifetz-Tussman, Khayem; Heller, Binim; Luria, Tsvi; Mlotek, Yosl; Ratson, Khave; Rozenburg, Sh.; Schaechter, Mordkhe; Shamir, Aryeh; Shapiro, S.; Shedletski, A.; Shor, Zalman; Sutzkever, Avrom; Turkow, Zigmund; Verber, Shifre; Weinreich, Bine; Weinreich, Max; Weinreich, Uriel; Yagur, Moyshe; Yakir, Ruti; Yungman, Moyshe; Zelitch, Yehude; I.L. Peretz Publishers; Israeli Broadcasting Service; Congress for Jewish Culture; Workmen's Circle
    - Correspondence in, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Aleksander, M.; Ash, Khayele; Barkan, Khayem; Codor, Esther; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Shaff, Judith; Shaff, Martin; Shoval, Yehudi; Shoval, Gedi; Shteynberg, Mordkhe; Sutzkever, Avrom; Vaysman, Gavriel; Weinreich, Aliza; I.L. Peretz Publishers; Israeli Broadcasting Service; Congress for Jewish Culture; Workmen's Circle
    - Correspondence in, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Dzuba, Albert; Dzuba, Selma; Eisenman, Tsvi; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Rosenstein, Tevye; Seltzer, Arlene; Sharon, N.; Sutzkever, Avrom; Tsitron, N.; Weinreich, Bine; Yiddish Writers and Journalists Assoc. in Israel
    - Correspondence in, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Also includes telegram from Gella Schweid Fishman and Joshua A. Fishman.
      Aguzi, Moshe; Codor, Esther; Cohen, Rivke; Eisenman, Tsvi; Fairstein, Khane; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Grosbard, Hertz; Hochberg, Shloyme; Khalomish, Mordkhe; Mikom, Moshe; Miller, Shmarya; Missotten, Paul; Sadan, Dov; Schaechter, Mordkhe; Sharon, Nokhum; Sutzkever, Avrom; Tsitron, N.; Weinreich, Bine; Assoc. of Yiddish Authors & Journalists of Israel; Hashomer Hatsair; Yugutruf
    - Correspondence in, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Aguzi, Moshe; Ayzntsvayg, Numa; Basman, Rivke; Beker, Yaakov; Birshteyn, Yosl; Codor, Esther; Cohen, Ita; Eisenman, Tsvi; Fairstein, Khane; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Gros-Tsimerman, M.; Halevi, Binyamin; Hrushovski, Rina; Hrushovski, Benjamin; Kahara, Shulamit; Karvin, Dani; Khalomish, M.; Loyter, Lili; Olitski, Leyb; Schaechter, Mordkhe; Sharon, Nokhum; Shomri, Arye; Sigalovski, N.; Sutzkever, Avrom; Tsitron, N.; Verber, Shifra; Weinreich, Bine; Assoc. of Yiddish Authors and Journalists of Israel; Harshav; Israel Book Publishing House; Office of President of Israel; Yiddish Dept. of Mapam
    - Correspondence in, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Alos includes children's book about Jewish holidays and Rukhl Fishman's contract with Alef Publishers.
      Abramowicz, Dina; Beker, Yaakov; Birshteyn, Yosl; Codor, Esther; Fishman, Aaron; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Heifetz-Tusman, Malke; Landau, Khayem; Levi, Dror; Levin, Leova; Luria, Tsvi; Miron, Dan; Olitski, Leyb; Schaechter, Mordkhe; Sharon, Nokhum; Simon, Solomon; Sutzkever, Avrom; Weinreich, Bine; Yafe, A.B.; Yungman, Moyshe; Al-Hamishmar; Alef Pubishers; Histadrut; Yisroel Stime; Yivo
    - Correspondence in, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Abramowicz, Dina; Beker, Yaakov; Birshteyn, Yosl; Codor, Esther; Cohen, Meyer; Cohen, Rivka; Dzuba, Selma; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Heifetz-Tusman, Malke; Khanivits, Gershon; Khalomish, Mordkhe; Lederman, I.M.; Miron, Dan; Okhmani, Azriel; Orenstein, Eugen; Schaechter, Mordkhe; Sharon, Nokhum; Shedletski, Efrayem; Shomri, Arieh; Shor, Yitskhok; Simon, Solomon; Sutzkever, Avrom; Weinreich, Bine; Yaffe, Meyer; Yakir, Ruti; Yungman, Moyshe; Al-Hamishmar; Alef Pubishers; Hashomer Hatsair; Histadrut; Kibutz Eyen-Dor; Yisroel Stime; Yivo
    - Correspondence in, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Includes correspondence from Joshua A. Fishman to Arik Holdheim and Aliza Holdheim.
      Aharoni, Arye; Codor, Esther; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Holdheim, Aliza; Holdheim, Arik; Sutzkever, Avrom; Kibutz "Reshefin"
    - Correspondence in, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Includes correspondence from Joshua A. Fishman regarding his research
      Baraban, Avrom; Codor, Esther; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Netser, Eli; Sadan, Dov; Shamir, Yosef; Shomri, Arye; Sutzkever, Avrom; Waldman, Moyshe; Kibutz HaShomer HaTsair; Yisroel-Bukh
    - Correspondence in, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Davis, Moshe; Fishman, Sonia; Ginsburg, Edward; Netser, Eli; Revsin, Rivkin; Schaecter, Mordkhe; Shomri, Arye; Singer, Isaac Bashevis; Sutzkever, Avrom; Zelitch, Yehude; Kibutz Hashomer Hatsair; Office of President of the State Department of Information on the Jewish People in Diaspora; Benyumen Skekhter Foundation for the Advancement of Standard Yiddish; Yisroel-Bukh Publishing House
    - Correspondence in, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Sonia; Fishman, Joshua A.; Kaspi, Yehudah; Kharif, Yosl; Loyter, Lili; Schaecter, Mordkhe; Shtaisel, Blume; Zelitch, Yehude; Benyumen Skekhter Foundation for the Advancement of Standard Yiddish
    - Correspondence in, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Includes an invitation to evening in honor of Avrom Karpinovitsh on the publication of his book.
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Heifetz-Tussman, Malke; Karpinovitsh, Avrom; Litvin, Mordkhe; Roskies, David; Sutzkever, Avrom; Top, Shmuel; Winer, Gershan; Yidishe Kultur Gezelshaft, Jerusalem
    - Correspondence in, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      The correspondence from Joshua A. Fishman includes a letter from Meushar Agib, Nev Aviv.
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Kestin-Heller, Hadassah; Kharif, Yosl; Litvin, Mordkhe; Rock, Stella; Shternfeld, S.; Waldman, Moyshe; Leiwick-House
    - Correspondence in, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Codor, Esther; Fishman, Gella Schweid; Fishman, Joshua A.; Fishman, Sonia; Friedman, Kenya; Litvin, Mordkhe; Noy, Dov; Rock, Stella; Sheinman family; Hebrew University of Jerusalem
    - Correspondence in, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Correspondence from B. Sherman includes a press clipping about Joshua A. Fishman's request for a visa to travel to the Soviet Union being denied. Also includes a returned check from Joshua A. Fishman to Rukhl Fishman. Correspondence includes a note from the United Workers Party about a literary event in which Rukhl Fishman participated. Also includes a copy of a letter from Joshua A. Fishman to Kenya Friedman and Lili Loyter.